How to insert an element into artillery at specific position.
This is very important and common a question that may be asked in the interview or in exam.
We need to insert element of value 60 at index, do we have an array and array of five elements?
Array of zero equal to an array of one equals 20 at index to 30 at index, three for the index for IS
50 and position equal to two.
We need at the position of two to make the change, so we need to insert.
We not we don't need to update.
We need to insert 60 at an index to.
And make this out of a bigger plus one than that, any show at me.
So.
We have initially created an array and realized the value of values of it, 10, 20, 30, 40 and 50,
we need to insert at Index two, which is at 30.
Before 30 we need between 20 and 30.
We need to insert 60.
So we create these variables position if what the two sides equal to five elements equal to 60.
And till now we have created this array.
We have initialized 10, 20, 30, 40 and 50.
This is our array.
We need to insert at index to the 6th.
So between 20 and 30, we need to insert 60.
Let's see how our example looks.
This is very important.
I need from you to understand and concentrate with me and write these down to memorize them later.
OK.
For doing that, I can't make like a rate at index to equal to 60, because at this time I can I am
updating, so I have removed 30 and put six.
I don't need like this.
I need to insert 60 between 20 and 30.
We need for this purpose to make the use of forward loop that starts inversely from IE equal to size,
so it will start from size a greater than position.
So I will stop at the position that we need to insert and I minus minus so it will go backward from
the last element of the array and backward till reaching that element and index position equal to two.
OK.
So.
It would start by creating a new.
Array element, an empty one array of eye equal array of five minus one.
This is the key of the solution for this question.
We need to shift that.
So how it works.
It will start shifting the elements into a new position, so I array of equal array of five minus one.
It will shift the elements.
Shift 30.
That now I reach his position, so I the iteration of this array reaches that element at index to.
Our position equal to two and at the start shifting array of equal array I minus one.
The last step when this started, this array stops.
We put array at position, which we need and we need to make, which is equal to to equal the element
which is equal to sixth.
At this time, we have created this.
We have inserted an element into and as a specific position.
The complexity of this operation and the best case scenario is of one, because if we need to insert
an element at index zero.
At index, sorry, at index, the last index, it's very simple now inserting element and index five.
Sorry, inserting element and element at least index because the last index will create and open a new
tab and insert it directly.
Best case is a one.
But if we need to insert, the worst case is inserting element at the first position.
We have seen that this shifting, this is shifting the elements to that.
It will make this complexity, this the functionality and this algorithm works more to shift the elements
when we are going to lessen the.
And so as the index decreased, this algorithm need more time to be.